



















Mayur Bakaraniya

Career Objective:

- ❖ To grow with the organization by learning new things with each new assignment
- To use my skills in the best possible ways for achieving the company's goal

Summary of Skills & Experience:

Total 16+ years of experience in Computer Hardware, Network equipment's, Servers, Security Surveillance and Payment solution products like KIOSK, BNA, MICR and CCPC, ATM, CRM, BNA, RCM, DCV for the **Site Sourcing to Cash live/Tech live.** In addition, **Cash Logistics, Recon, Audit of Sites, SLM Operations, Feasibilities, Project Management, Cost Optimization, Data Analysis, SLA management, Warehouse Management, Asset Management, Vendor Management, Infrastructure Deployment** are a major part of my profile.

Achievements & Certifications:

- **❖ MICROSOFT CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL** DEC − 2005
- **❖ CISCO CERTIFIED NETWORK ASSOCIATED** JAN − 2006
- ❖ NCR ATM BASIC CE CERTIFICATION JUNE 2010
- **❖ NCR ADVANCE ATM CE CERTIFICATION** JAN − 2013
- **❖ MPHASIS SERVICE DELIVERY EXCELLENCE AWARD** MARCH − 2013
- **❖ MPHASIS SERVICE DELIVERY EXCELLENCE AWARD** MARCH − 2014
- **❖ Business Analysis & Process Management Coursera**, MARCH 2023
- Introduction to Data Analysis using Microsoft Excel Coursera , MARCH 2023
- ❖ Introduction to Microsoft Excel Coursera , MARCH 2023
- Using Basic Formulas and Functions in Microsoft Excel Coursera , MARCH 2023





















Technical Skills:

- Operating Systems: Installation and configuration Windows 3.11, 95, 98, Me, XP, vista, 7, 8.1, 10 Linux, UNIX
- Network Devices: Installation, configuration and troubleshooting of ADSL and Dial-up modem, Wireless Routers, Cisco Series routers, Manageable switches and other network equipment's.
- ❖ Payment Solution Products: Installation, configuration and troubleshooting of ATM, GBNA, KIOSK, MICR, CCPC, Thermal and Dot matrix Printers, Camera, and etc.
- Servers: Installation and troubleshooting of HP & Dell servers with different OS.
- Security Surveillance: Installation, configuration and troubleshooting of Figure print, Card access, FACEID, all types of DVR, Indoor cameras, Outdoor cameras, PTZ cameras, and etc. products related to security.

Work Experience:

Working as Regional Operation Manager in CMS Info Systems Limited with the Gujarat Locations from 25-Aug-2020 to 28-Feb-23.

- ❖ Working for the smooth operations of ATMs, RCMs and Direct Cash Vans the South Zone of Gujarat.
- ❖ Managing 1800+ ATMs, 1000+RCMs & 15+DCVs in region.
- Arrangement of the feasibilities for upcoming business point within TAT.
- ❖ I am looking the vendor management to get the services as per the SLA.
- Managing the 6 Branches, Call center and 1 Regional Office with direct indirect Field staff of 600+ manpower.
- Helping the organization to find out the resources related to business verticals.
- Contributing / Managing departments like, HR/Admin/Accounts/Legal/Audit/Reconciliation/Call Center under my Proview as per business need.

Working as Manager – Service Delivery in Transaction Solution International India Pvt. Ltd. with the Gujarat Locations from 1st April 2016 to 24-Jul-2020.

- Looking the Downtime tickets of Whole Gujarat ATMs to reduce the downtime of the sites.
- Site sourcing to Cash live done for 2340 ATMs & Managing 1000+ ATMs in Gujarat post closer.
- Working on the SLA Management to get the uptime as required by the client.
- ❖ Working on the projects to improve the TXNs on the ATMs deploy by us.
- ❖ I am looking the vendor management to get the services as per the SLA.
- Managing 35+ team of direct indirect FTE members for Gujarat.
- I am looking the site sourcing as per the requirement of the organization to improve the transaction.
- Managing the vendors to complete the work for TIS / commissioning of assets within the TAT.
- ❖ I am doing the relocations of ATMs from the low hit sites to the high hit sites.
- Checking the site feasibility as per the requirements like No TXNs, Security Level of the area, Infrastructure, Rentals, etc.
- Looking the Leasing, licensing & Rental issues including negotiation and issuing of annexures for Gujarat Region
- ❖ I am looking the TIS issues like, UPS/Network/ATM/Infrastructure, etc.
- I am Looking Office Administration including the vendor payments, asset management including warehouse management.





















Worked as Senior Regional Lead – Service Delivery in Mphasis with the Gujarat Locations from 16th April 2013 to 31st March 2016.

- Looking the Downtime tickets of Whole Gujarat ATMs to reduce the downtime of the sites.
- ❖ Site sourcing to Cash live done for 2340 ATMs & Managing 1000+ ATMs in Gujarat post closer.
- Working on the SLA Management to get the uptime as required by the client.
- ❖ Working on the projects to improve the TXNs on the ATMs deploy by us.
- I am looking the vendor management to get the services as per the SLA.
- ❖ Managing 35+ team of direct indirect FTE members for Gujarat.
- I am looking the site sourcing as per the requirement of the organization to improve the transaction.
- Managing the vendors to complete the work for TIS / commissioning of assets within the TAT.
- ❖ I am doing the relocations of ATMs from the low hit sites to the high hit sites.
- Checking the site feasibility as per the requirements like No TXNs, Security Level of the area, Infrastructure, Rentals, etc.
- Looking the Leasing, licensing & Rental issues including negotiation and issuing of annexures for Gujarat Region
- ❖ I am looking the TIS issues like, UPS/Network/ATM/Infrastructure, etc.
- ❖ I am Looking Office Administration including the vendor payments, asset management including warehouse management.

Worked as Customer Engineer in NCR Corporation India Pvt. Ltd. within the Gujarat Locations from 3rd Sep 2012 to 15th Apr 2013.

- ❖ I was looking my area with so many banking clients like, SBI, HDFC, UBI, AXIS, ICICI, IDBI, MUCB, OBC and many more along with 24x7 supports.
- I was looking the customer calls like, device not working due to the hardware of the machine got failure, some software got malfunctioning, some bills got shorted or excesses and bills got jam and stuck frequently.
- In the part of technical view, I have done the calibration and configuration of the devices like dispenser mechanism, card reader, cameras, thermal and dot matrix printers, pc core, software migration, network and etc.
- ❖ I helped my bank clients when they stuck into the reconciliation.
- ❖ I manage the multiple calls on the priority basis as per the company standard and finished it within the SLA.
- Looking at the PMs and Activities like, software migration, device up gradation and provide the training to the customer if required.

Worked as Branch Head for the Reliance Security at South Sudan Juba Location from 14th Dec 2011 to 14th Feb 2012

- I was looking the operation for the CCTV Surveillance systems, Biometric Access Control installation, Network equipment's deployment and etc.
- Finished the project within the timeframe along with the training to the customer.
- I am having depth knowledge about the Figure print, Card access, FACEID, all types of DVR, Indoor cameras, Outdoor cameras, PTZ cameras, and etc. products related to security surveillance along with the part of the configuration of each product.





















Worked as Customer Support specialist in NCR Corporation India Pvt. Ltd. within the Gujarat Locations from 24th Dec 2008 to 30th Nov2011

- ❖ I was looking my area with so many banking clients like, SBI, HDFC, UBI, AXIS, ICICI, IDBI, MUCB, OBC and many more along with 24x7 support.
- ❖ I was looking the customer calls like, device not working due to the hardware of the machine got failure, some software got malfunctioning, some bills got shorted or excesses and bills got jam and stuck frequently.
- ❖ In the part of technical view, I have done the calibration and configuration of the devices like dispenser mechanism, card reader, cameras, thermal and dot matrix printers, pc core, software migration, network and etc.
- ❖ I helped my bank clients when they stuck into the reconciliation.
- ❖ I manage the multiple calls on the priority basis as per the company standard and finished it within the SLA.
- Looking at the PMs and Activities like, software migration, device up gradation and provide the training to the customer if required.

Worked as ATM Service Representative in NCR Corporation India Pvt. Ltd. through Onward eservices Ltd From 1st June 2007 to 16th June 2008 for the Junagadh region

- I was looking my area with so many banking clients like, SBI, HDFC, UBI, AXIS, ICICI, IDBI, MUCB, OBC and many more along with 24x7 support.
- ❖ I was looking the customer calls like, device not working due to the hardware of the machine got failure, some software got malfunctioning, some bills got shorted or excesses and bills got jam and stuck frequently.
- ❖ In the part of technical view, I have done the calibration and configuration of the devices like dispenser mechanism, card reader, cameras, thermal and dot matrix printers, pc core, software migration, network and etc.
- ❖ I helped my bank clients when they stuck into the reconciliation.
- I manage the multiple calls on the priority basis as per the company standard and finished it within the SLA.
- Looking at the PMs and Activities like, software migration, device up gradation and provide the training to the customer if required.
- Provide the 24x7 telephonic supports to the client when they needed.

Worked as a Customer Support Engineer for CRAZY COMPUTERS Junagadh from 1st May-2005 to 31st of May 2007

- I was looking the AMC of our company in a schools and colleges and government entities.
- I had done sales promotional activities at concerned to our business.
- ❖ I am working with all the OS like Win 2000, Win 2003, Win XP, Win 98, Linux and active directory, Group Polices and mail messenger like Outlook Express, Microsoft Outlook 2000, Microsoft Outlook 2003.
- Resolve the technical issue at the remote sites like PC hardware, Printers, ADSL modems, dial-up modems, and etc.

Education & Qualification:

❖ S.S.C. – March – 1999.

From, Manas Bharati Vidhya Bhavan in GSEB

❖ H.S.C. – July – 2001.

From, Swami Vivekanand Vinay Mandir in GHSEB

❖ BACHELOR OF COMPUTER APPLICATION (BCA). October − 2005.

From Patel Kelavani Mandal College of Tech. in SAURASHTRA UNIVERSITY





















Personal Details:

Fathers Name: Aravind Bhai Bakaraniya

❖ Date of Birth: 29th August 1984.

❖ Sex: Male

Marital Status: Married

Nationality: Indian

❖ Passport No: W6885046

Reallocation: Any where

Languages known: English, Hindi and Gujarati

Hobbies: Listening music, Surfing on Net.

Current Address: M – 1002, Eden Tower, Godrej Garden City, Jagatpur, Ahmedabad – 382470 (Gujarat) INDIA

❖ Permanent Address: Street No. 4, Dubdi Plot, Kailash Nagar, Junagadh – 362001 (Gujarat) INDIA

Note: I require sponsorship if the position is outside the India.

I here declare that all the above information furnished by me in this resume is best of my knowledge.

Date: / /

Place: B. MAYUR